<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Crowd Interactive Tech Blog</title>
 <link href="http://blog.crowdint.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://blog.crowdint.com/"/>
 <updated>2011-06-02T01:21:19-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://blog.crowdint.com/</id>
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vagrant to manage multiple dev environments</title>
   <link href="http://blog.crowdint.com/2011/06/02/vagrant.html"/>
   <updated>2011-06-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.crowdint.com/2011/06/02/vagrant</id>
   <photo>29612de9aa10447dc2f9ec84cf2ab1b2</photo>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Using Vagrant to manage different dev environments, services and configurations.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lets start rocking like a pro. Installing services (like mysql, redis, mongo..) in your own machine is old fashioned&lt;/em&gt;. Don't let you handle with different versions, as different configurations, and most of the time your dev machine isn't the same as your production server. That's why Vagrant came for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vagrant let you create different virtualized machines, easy and separated from your computer internals. So, you can easy handle all your dev environments (like dev, stage, production..) including specific versions of server and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I'm working in two projects, and both uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://mongodb.org&quot;&gt;mongodb&lt;/a&gt; as primary database but locked with different (and incompatible) versions. So, I've started using Vagrant to handle that. I need one version, I just start the box that contains that server, and I don't mess with my real system. That's why Vagrant is so important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://virtualbox.org&quot;&gt;Virtualbox&lt;/a&gt; inside, it supports command line, easy ssh access, easy distribution, shared folders, and other goodies.
Even you can package your box, and distribute it to all your team members. One suprem box for rule them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will require &lt;em&gt;ruby&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;rubygems&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;virtualbox 4&lt;/em&gt; installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install vagrant
vagrant --help
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Creating a new box&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir ~/Vagrants;
cd ~/Vagrants/;
vagrant box add base http://files.vagrantup.com/lucid32.box;
vagrant init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes:&lt;/em&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;vagrant box add&lt;/code&gt; command will download a pre-created ubuntu linux system (so ~260Mb will be downloaded)
Vagrant uses one configuration file per box, and it's called &lt;code&gt;VagrantFile&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Starting your box&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/Vagrants/;
vagrant up
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thats it. You have a new Linux environment ready to be configured, be installed by your software, servers, services, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; if you require directly access from outside to your box, just enable the ssh access editing the &lt;code&gt;VagrantFile&lt;/code&gt;, and uncommenting this: &lt;code&gt;config.vm.network &quot;33.33.33.10&quot;&lt;/code&gt;. For example, if you're configuring an MySQL instance, your client will connect to 33.33.33.10:3606.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Accessing it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, all you need install your servers. It's just like log in into your servers, do some apt-get install, configure your settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ~/Vagrants/;
vagrant ssh
# sudo apt-get install your-stuff-1.2.3
exit
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Power OFF, suspend, resume..&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's easy as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;vagrant halt
vagrant suspend
vagrant resume
vagrant destroy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;And that's it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it's your time. Try it, learn it, use it, enjoy it.
&lt;em&gt;And see you next time!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;More info&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More info at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://vagrant.com&quot;&gt;vagrant.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/softr8&quot;&gt;Edwin&lt;/a&gt;, for his first explanation about Vagrant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
   <author>
     <name>Mario Zaizar</name>
     <email>mario@crowdint.com</email>
   </author>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Railsconf 2011</title>
   <link href="http://blog.crowdint.com/2011/05/24/railsconf-2011.html"/>
   <updated>2011-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.crowdint.com/2011/05/24/railsconf-2011</id>
   <photo>d32b52ec6403614b1adf3e648cbbe584</photo>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, a good part of our team flew to Baltimore for Railsconf 2011. As
every year, it was a ton of fun, there was a lot to learn and it was inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love going to conferences, not just because of the talks, but, because you
get to meet people. I like talking to the persons that wrote the gems that
I use everyday and thank them for their effort in creating awesome code so
we don't have to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2011/05/24/guns.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Crowd Interactive team&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And not just gem writers, it's also fun to meet all those other Ruby
developers that enjoy using Rails and everything else as much as I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2011/05/24/sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The sign&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing you can take out of the experience is inspiration.
Inspiration to follow the leaders. Inspiration to collaborate to open
source. Or, as Corey Haines said on his keynote, inspiration to be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2011/05/24/friends.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Friends at Railsconf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we enjoy confences so much, last year we were bummed that there was not
a lot of Ruby conferences in Mexico so we organized
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.magmarails.com&quot;&gt;Magma Rails&lt;/a&gt;, and it ended
up being better than expected. this year we're organizing its second edition
and it's going to be twice as awesome as last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're moving to Manzanillo Colima, since this year we are inviting people
from all over the world, it makes more sense to have it at a tourist friendly
city. You will be able to smell the ocean from your seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.magmarails.com&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.magmarails.com/images/foto-magma.png&quot; alt=&quot;Last year&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now we're looking for &lt;a href=&quot;http://http://www.magmarails.com/callforpapers&quot;&gt;speakers&lt;/a&gt;
and sponsors, contact us if you're interested. I promise it will be a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
   <author>
     <name>David Padilla</name>
     <email>david@crowdint.com</email>
   </author>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to Sinatra + Haml + Compass(SCSS) + Blueprint</title>
   <link href="http://blog.crowdint.com/2011/04/06/sinatra-haml-compass-blueprint.html"/>
   <updated>2011-04-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://blog.crowdint.com/2011/04/06/sinatra-haml-compass-blueprint</id>
   <photo>fa56812143dd6049ef19d1a8032f21da</photo>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I spent about half a day trying to get Sinatra working
with Compass and Blueprint. At first, it was a pain in the ass because the
documentation is pretty lame. But after some reading here and there and
trying via command line, I failed again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, don't despair, there is hope... I got it to work eventually and here is how I did it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you have to setup your sinatra app as usual.
If you have read
&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.crowdint.com/2011/03/14/Sinatra-the-green-way.html&quot;&gt;Omar's post about setting up your sinatra app with test&lt;/a&gt;
you know what I'm talking about. Take a look at it if you haven't.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very easy to setup your sinatra apps, a couple of minutes and you're done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also fork my ready-to-use github repo &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/hecbuma/sinatra-blueprint&quot;&gt;Sinatra+Haml+Compas+Blueprint&lt;/a&gt;
and make your changes there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The real deal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, now that we have our sinatra app, it's time to add some stuff so we are able
to use Haml and Compass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First add these gems to you Gemfile (Compass and Haml). You will end up with something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have to add a config file for compass:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and add this content to it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I've changed the css_dir and the image dir to use &quot;public&quot; instead of &quot;static&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, we are half way there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let's add some more configuration for compass, but this time in your app file (myapp.rb):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this you are telling compass to automatically convert SCSS files into CSS files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the final touch: let's setup blueprint for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that is all. I hope this is helpful for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
   <author>
     <name>Hector Bustillos</name>
     <email>hector.bustillos@crowdint.com</email>
   </author>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
